Kajal Thakare

Kajalm.thakare@gmail.com **Data Scientist**







https://github.com/kajalmthakare www.linkedin.com/in/kajal2399

Summary

With one year of experience as a Data Scientist and two years of experience as Data Executive Officer, proficient in python3, SQL and data visualisation tools with a knack for uncovering valuable insights.

Tech Stack

Data Science/ Machine Learning/ Deep Learning

Python3, Data Visualisation, Supervised learning algorithms, Unsupervised Learning algorithms,

ANN, CNN, EDA, Feature Engineering, Feature selection & extraction etc.

Mathematics for ML & DL

Probability, Statistics, Matrices

Python packages and Frameworks

Scikit - Learn, TensorFlow, Keras, NumPy, Pandas, PySpark, SciPy, OOP

Tools

SQL, MongoDB, GitHub, Financial Tools

Visualization

PowerBI, Tableau

Cloud Deployment

AWS, Azure

Analysing Large Datasets

Big Data, TimeSeries

Education: -

Linguistic Capabilities: -

2023	Advance Data Science & Al		English	
2020	Banking & Insurance (BBI) MU	9.20 CGPA	Hindi	
2017	HSC – Maharashtra State Borad	80.46 %	Marathi	
2015	SSC - Maharashtra State Board	75.60 %	Sanskrit	

Experience: -

(May 2023 – Apr 2024) (Internship) – Data Scientist | LearnBay | Remote

(March 2021 - Dec 2022) (Full Time) - Data Executive Officer | Vat IT | Thane

(Jan 2019 - March 2019) (Internship) - Accountant | VPS Ltd. and Jankhulasa Newspaper pvt. ltd.

Personal ML Projects: -

While the resume highlights selected projects, a comprehensive portfolio is available on my <u>GitHub</u> profile

Cab Booking Prediction: -

This is the classification problem-based dataset where I need to predict the cab booking is going to confirmed or cancelled with the help of different algorithms and analysis after the EDA part I build 3 different end – to – end model.

Healthcare Ultrasound Machine: -

While ensuring the accuracy of the ultrasound machine and to save the time by reducing the testing points of the machine with the help of feature engineering and dimensionality reduction I built a model using various techniques and algorithms

Courier Company Delivery charges: -

With the help of Five different excel files I need to find out the difference between the actual and charges charged by the courier company and provide the excel sheet contain the difference between paid and actual charges.

Bankruptcy Prediction: -

From the given data of companies' financial performance, I need to build a model to predict the company is going to be bankrupt or financially heathy in future which help to take future and investment decisions.

I solemnly declare that the above information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

(Kajal M. Thakare)